# **VANESSA PETIT**

vpetitwork@gmail.com • 917-330-1630

Versatile bilingual writer, editor and translator with extensive experience in creating original content and concepts in English and Spanish across many platforms: digital, social media, print, marketing campaigns and book publishing. I specialize in creative translation and transcreation helping brands find their voice in English and Spanish prioritizing the ideas behind the words.

### **EDUCATION**

# Combined B.A. and M.A. in Political Science University of Belgrano

Buenos Aires, Argentina

# B.A in Journalism and Communications

Pontifical Catholic University of Argentina Buenos Aires, Argentina

# Certificate Program in Broadcast Journalism

School of Continuing and Professional Studies New York University

To view samples of my work visit vanessapetit.com

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Uniworld Group-UWG, NY

2021 - Present

Bilingual Proofreader/ Editor

Proof all aspects of integrated marketing campaigns in both English and Spanish, spanning across print, digital assets, radio and video scripts and pitch decks.

■ Ensure there are no spelling or grammatical errors in both languages and the English translates correctly into Spanish and copy edit accordingly.

# New York State Department of Health, NY

**Case Investigator** 

2021-2022

Responsible for receiving reports of persons suspected or confirmed as having COVID-19, locating them, and interviewing them in order to gather information necessary for public health case investigation and contact tracing.

- Ascertain whether the case is part of a group at high risk of transmission or severe disease and provide information/education about the illness and methods of disease prevention and control, including the importance of staying isolated from others.
- Responsible for coordinating with epidemiologists who are investigating outbreaks and disease occurrence in congregate settings. Entering data into a statewide tracking system.

#### The Avon Company, NY

2020 - 2021

**Spanish Translator and Communications Specialist** 

Translate, edit, and proofread English to Spanish pamphlets, brochures, flyers, and digital content on avon.com. Develop original communication content for all brands in Spanish to ensure cultural relevance, editorial accuracy, and consistency in media campaigns.

- Collaborate as an interdepartmental liaison on all editorial functions and standards while collaborating with Incentives, Events, and marketing teams.
- Help build brand awareness and support the communication strategies of Representatives and their customers
- Provide translation, editing, and proofreading of time-sensitive and confidential materials from English to Spanish to ensure that translations are appropriate for the target audience.

# Self-Employed

2016 - Present

**Content Creator, Writer, Editor, and Translator** 

Develop and write content for different websites and business projects. Assist brands in media content development. Translate content in Spanish to engage native clients

■ Marriott Bonvoy Traveler en Español: Establish international customer engagement by creating travel content in Spanish to assist guests in exploring highlighted locations within Latin America, such as Brazil, Costa Rica, Colombia, Argentina, and Uruguay.

# **VANESSA PETIT**

vpetitwork@gmail.com • 917-330-1630

#### **KEY SKILLS**

Native English and Spanish speaker

Multimedia reporting

Demonstrable experience producing relevant content to target audiences

Proofreading/editing/ top editing

Research and fact Checking

Excellent written communicational skills in both languages

Ability to meet tight deadlines

Work well Independently and as part of a team

Creative thinker with outstanding interpersonal skills

Social media marketing campaigns

Biography drafting/writing

Translation of books into Spanish

#### **TECHNOLOGY**

#### Working Knowledge of:

InDesign / Incopy

Photoshop

Good understanding of CMS and SEO

Social Media best practices

MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

### References:

**Upon Request** 

- Story Terrace: Work as a biographer/ book writer. Interview clients who want to create a narrative story about their lives and accomplishments and or hardships. Conduct interviews and then write long form narratives. I also proofread and edit Spanish language books written by other writers.
- Common Sense Media: Translate into Spanish all media related content (movies, TV shows, books, and video games) for the website to help parents make good entertainment choices for their kids.
- **Siempre Mujer:** Developed/translated content for print edition of Mood board and Gran estreno sections and for digital platforms,
- Moroccan Oil: Boosted sales growth of Moroccan oil by translating ads, brochures, products, messages, and marketing content from English to Spanish along with print edition catalogues for associate salons.
- What to Expect: Enhanced knowledge of parenting, health, bilingualism, and biculturalism for millennial Latina moms by writing articles in English for the website.
- **NY Metro Parent:** Developed website content and proofread print edition for Things to do section.

# **Meredith Corporation, NY**

2006 - 2015

**Deputy Editor, Ser Padres Media Group** 

Assisted Editor-in-Chief in planning and execution of editorial content, including the writing/ editing content, and complying with production schedules for print edition and online platforms. Streamlined workflow by creating monthly and yearly editorial calendars. Maintained writing standards while managing freelance writer team. Collaborated with marketing/sales departments on partnership ideas and translating culturally relevant content for clients. Developed media understanding through active participation in various segments of CNN, Better TV en Español, Univision, and Telemundo.

- Ensured consistency and cultural relevance in content creation while supervising editorial content of Ser Padres, Bebé and Espera publications.
- Established brand recognition by writing, editing, and proofreading content related to fashion, beauty, women's health, relationships, parenting, culture, pregnancy, development, advice/first-person features.
- Maintained customer engagement while managing websites by finding talent for celebrity covers and providing content for site/social media platforms.
- Improved brand perception by speaking readership/clients at events and presentations.

### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Managing Editor, Latina Magazine, Latina Media Ventures, NY
- Reporter for Spanish Online Desk, Associated Press, NY
- Editorial Assistant, Associated Press, Miami, Forida
- Assistant Reporter / Researcher, Los Angeles Times, Buenos Aires, Argentina